<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Awards on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/</link><description>Recent content in Awards on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SIGSOFT Awards Overview</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/sigsoftawards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/sigsoftawards/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="acm-sigsoft-awards">ACM SIGSOFT Awards&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>ACM SIGSOFT recognizes excellence in software engineering through several
awards, presented annually. These awards honor outstanding contributions to our
field, throughout our colleagues&amp;rsquo; careers. Awards are typically presented to
individuals, but can be awarded jointly when circumstances warrant, such as for
joint contributions. Awards are not given posthumously.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="award-categories">Award Categories&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="senior-awards">Senior Awards&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/distinguishedservice/">Distinguished Service
Award&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> - Recognizes
dedicated and important service to the software engineering community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/outstandingresearch/">Outstanding Research Award&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> - Honors
significant and lasting research contributions to the theory or practice of
software engineering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/influentialeducator/">Influential Educator Award&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> - Celebrates
significant contributions and impact on software engineering education as a
teacher, mentor, researcher, author, and/or policy maker&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="junior-awards">Junior Awards&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/dissertation/">Outstanding Doctoral Dissertation Award&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> - Presented to the author of an outstanding doctoral dissertation in software engineering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/earlycareerresearcher/">Early Career Researcher Award&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> - Recognizes outstanding contributions by early career investigators&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/anger/">Frank Anger Memorial Award&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> - Student travel award promoting cross-disciplinary research between SIGSOFT and SIGBED communities&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="impact-award">Impact Award&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/impactpaper/">Impact Paper Award&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> - Recognizes papers from SIGSOFT conferences that have had significant influence&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="nomination-process">Nomination Process&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All awards follow a similar nomination process, with two key deadlines:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title> ACM SIGSOFT - SIGBED Frank Anger Award</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/anger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/anger/</guid><description>&lt;p>In honor of our late colleague and friend, Dr. Frank Anger, the ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering has joined together with the &lt;a href="https://sigbed.org/">ACM Special Interest Group on Embedded Systems&lt;/a> to present the Frank Anger Memorial Award. Dr. Frank Anger, an outstanding national leader in the field of software engineering, died in a tragic automobile accident on July 8, 2004. One of Frank&amp;rsquo;s primary goals was supporting the crossover of ideas between research communities engaged in software. As an outstanding scientist and recognized national leader in computer science, he worked toward this goal until his untimely death.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title> Distinguished Paper Award</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/distinguishedpaper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/distinguishedpaper/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="acm-sigsoft-distinguished-paper-award">ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Paper Award&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ACM SIGSOFT encourages SIGSOFT-sponsored conferences to designate a number of accepted papers for ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Paper Awards for the conference. In addition to presenting certificates to the authors of awarded papers, two awarded papers from each ICSE, ESEC/FSE may be invited for presentation at the following Innovations in Software Engineering Conference (ISEC), which is sponsored by &lt;a href="https://www.cse.iitd.ernet.in/~sigcse/">SIGSE&lt;/a>, the Special Interest Group on Software Engineering of the Computer Society of India (CSI).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title> Distinguished Service Award</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/distinguishedservice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/distinguishedservice/</guid><description>&lt;p>This annual award is presented to individuals who have contributed dedicated and
important service to the software engineering community. The committee considers
all external nominations in the context of the nominees&amp;rsquo; specific and general
service contributions to the overall software engineering community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Criteria that the committee considers in evaluating nominations include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Service to ACM SIGSOFT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Service to the software engineering community outside of SIGSOFT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Service to broadening participation of underrepresented groups in software engineering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Service to students&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Length of time serving the software engineering community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Other service contributions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Consult the &lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/sigsoftawards/">main SIGSOFT Awards page&lt;/a> for key dates, nomination and eligibility instructions, and a link to the submission portal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title> Early Career Researcher Award</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/earlycareerresearcher/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/earlycareerresearcher/</guid><description>&lt;p>This award is presented to an individual or individuals who have made outstanding contributions in the area of software engineering as an early career investigator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be eligible for nomination for the award, individuals&amp;rsquo; most recent computer-related educational degree (baccalaureate, masters, or doctoral degree) must have been awarded no more than seven (7) years prior to the year of nomination e.g., a candidate who received a PhD at any point in 2018 is eligible to be nominated in the 2025 cycle (to receive an award in 2026). The 7-year window may be extended for extenuating circumstances such as parental or medical leave. Extenuating circumstances must be described in the nomination statement for the committee&amp;rsquo;s deliberation (the committee reserves the right to accept or deny the consideration of the extenuating circumstances).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title> Outstanding Doctoral Dissertation Award</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/dissertation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/dissertation/</guid><description>&lt;p>The SIGSOFT Outstanding Doctoral Dissertation Award is presented annually to the authors of outstanding doctoral dissertations in the area of Software Engineering. The author of winning dissertation(s) will be invited to publish a dissertation summary in the SIGSOFT newsletter, Software Engineering Notes (SEN).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The award is for an outstanding dissertation (in software engineering) dated within the year preceding the nomination due date. For nominations for the October 20, 2025, deadline, dissertations dated November, 2024 to November, 2025 are eligible. The dissertation date can refer to the “deposit date,” “committee approval date,” or another reasonable and relevant date, depending on the process followed by the nominee’s institution. However, please note that a dissertation can be nominated only once. Thus, if, e.g., the “deposit date” and “committee approval date” would fall into two award periods, the thesis cannot be nominated twice, and the nomination must choose one period. Especially given the time-specificity of this award, note that the selection committee is able to recognize multiple outstanding dissertations in a year, if circumstances warrant.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ACM SIGSOFT Impact Paper Award</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/impactpaper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/impactpaper/</guid><description>&lt;p>The ACM SIGSOFT Impact Paper Award is presented annually to the author(s) of a paper presented at a SIGSOFT-sponsored or co-sponsored conference held at least 11 years prior to the award year, e.g., for the October, 2025 deadline, papers published in 2015 or before or eligible. In including all of SIGSOFT&amp;rsquo;s conferences in the competition, this award recognizes the breadth and vitality of the software engineering community. The papers are judged by their influence since their publication.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Influential Educator Award</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/influentialeducator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/influentialeducator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Education is vital to the advancement of the research and practice of Software Engineering. Yet, the contributions of an educator often go unnoticed, except perhaps by those closest to the educator. The SIGSOFT Influential Educator Award is presented annually to an educator or educators who have made significant contributions to, and impact on, the field of software engineering with his or her accomplishments as a teacher, mentor, researcher (in education or learning), author, and/or policy maker.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Outstanding Research Award</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/outstandingresearch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/outstandingresearch/</guid><description>&lt;p>This award is presented to an individual or individuals who have made significant and lasting research contributions to the theory or practice of software engineering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the typical awards benefits, recipients are invited to give a keynote presentation at the ICSE conference in the year in which the award is made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consult the &lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/awards/sigsoftawards/">main SIGSOFT Awards page&lt;/a> for key dates, nomination and eligibility instructions, and a link to the submission portal.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>