<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Annualrpts on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/</link><description>Recent content in Annualrpts on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1995-1996 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/1996annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/1996annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-1995---june-1996">July, 1995 - June, 1996&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-lori-a-clarke-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: Lori A. Clarke, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT continued to have another active and successful year. The
highlights include a new student scholarship program, a very active
newsletter, an on-going award program, and a strong conference program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year we initiated a scholarship fund, &lt;strong>Conference Attendance
Program for Students (CAPS)&lt;/strong>, that will provide travel funds to
students to attend SIGSOFT sponsored conferences. It is hoped that CAPS
will encourage students to attend and to submit papers to software
engineering conferences. Under the direction of Mary Lou Soffa,
guidelines for the program were drafted, approved, announced in our
newsletter and posted on the web. An approval committee has been put in
place and funds were budgeted for support. Now we are waiting for our
first applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1996-1997 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/1997annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/1997annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-1996---june-1997">July, 1996 - June, 1997&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-lori-a-clarke-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: Lori A. Clarke, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT continues to be a vital organization that offers its members a
first rate newsletter and an excellent conference program. The
highlights of this last year are described below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT sponsors two major conferences each year, the International
Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE) and the Foundations of
Software Engineering(FSE), plus some specialized conferences and
workshops. FSE was held in San Francisco this year, with Mark Moriconi
serving as general chair and David Garlan as program chair. The speakers
and panels were selected to support the theme of the conference,
software architecture. There was a successful tutorial program and
attendance was up to 200 participants. Overall the technical program was
excellent and participant satisfaction seemed extremely high.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1997-1998 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/1998annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/1998annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-1997---june-1998">July, 1997 - June, 1998&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-david-notkin-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: David Notkin, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has had an excellent year, the first with a new set of officers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the awards front, we continued to make our annual service and
research awards. This year's ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Service award
was presented to Bruce Barnes, who was largely responsible for putting
an effective software engineering research program into place at NSF.
This year's ACM SIGSOFT Outstanding Research award was presented to
David Parnas, for his many contributions to the area of software design.
Joint with IEEE TCSE, we also continued to award the Most Influential
Paper from ICSE-10, which this year went to the ICSE-10 paper &lt;em>&amp;quot;On
Modeling and Analyzing System Behavior: Myths, Facts and Challenges&amp;quot;&lt;/em>,
authored by David Harel and colleagues. We made several awards to
students for travel support to SIGSOFT-sponsored conferences, under our
CAPS program. Several of the new ACM Fellows are members of SIGSOFT, a
fact that is very rewarding. As a final note, several years ago the
SIGSOFT Executive Committee agreed to have Program Committees name up to
10% of the papers from conferences as Distinguished Papers; we have,
however, never put this decision into action. We plan to do so this
year, also understanding that we need to clear this through the ACM
awards committee.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1997-1998 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/1999annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/1999annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-1998---june-1999">July, 1998 - June, 1999&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-david-notkin-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: David Notkin, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has had another strong year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the awards front, we continued to make our annual service and
research awards. This year's &lt;strong>ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Service
Award&lt;/strong> was presented to Bill Riddle, who has served the software
engineering community in innumerable ways (including serving as chair of
SIGSOFT a number of years ago). This year we awarded two &lt;strong>Outstanding
Research Awards&lt;/strong>. The first went, in a one-time posthumous award, to
Harlan Mills. The presentation was made to his widow at the Harlan Mills
memorial workshop, which was held at the 1999 International Conference
on Software Engineering in Los Angeles. The second went to Niklaus Wirth
and will be presented in Toulouse, France, at the ESEC/FSE joint
conference in September. Joint with IEEE TCSE, we also continued to
award the Most Influential Paper from ICSE N-10, which this year went to
the ICSE-11 paper &lt;em>&amp;quot;The Inscape Environment&amp;quot;&lt;/em>, authored by Dewayne
Perry. We made several awards to students for travel support to
SIGSOFT-sponsored conferences, under our CAPS program. Several of the
new ACM Fellows are members of SIGSOFT, a fact that is very rewarding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1999-2000 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2000annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2000annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-1999---june-2000">July 1999 - June 2000&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-david-notkin-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: David Notkin, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On behalf of SIGSOFT's membership and leadership, I'm happy to report
that we've had another strong year. We've continued our annual service
and research awards. Our Distinguished Service Award was presented to
Marv Zelkowitz, who has served the community in numerous ways for
several decades. Our Outstanding Research Award was awarded to Vic
Basili, for his many numerous contributions to research, especially in
empirical and experimental software engineering. As always, SIGSOFT
members were well represented in the ACM Fellows that were named this
year. (On the negative side, SIGSOFT --- in particular, I --- have
to follow through on two specific issues: putting the &amp;quot;Distinguished
Papers&amp;quot; into official form; and putting the research and service award
process into a more visible and clear state.) Our conference program
continues with great success. We've signed an agreement to hold the
annual SIGSOFT (FSE, Foundations of Software Engineering) conference in
2001, 2003, and 2005 jointly with the European Software Engineering
Conference, as we did in 1997 and 1999, as well. This continues building
international relationships and also addresses head-on the problem we
see with an unncessary and costly proliferation of conferences in
software engineering. Both FSE and ISSTA (our testing and analysis
conference) will be held on the West Coast of the US this year, with
strong planning and leadership teams in place for both. ICSE 2000 was a
success in Limerick, Ireland; next year, we'll be in Toronto for ICSE,
the first Canadian instance of the conference. I'd like to thank ---
really, since it's a thankless task! --- all the people, especially
the leadership teams, who have made the SIGSOFT conferences of the last
year such a success.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000-2001 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2001annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2001annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2000---june-2001">July 2000 - June 2001&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-david-notkin-chair">Submitted by: David Notkin, Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has had another strong year, and we are well-positioned to hand
off the leadership to our newly elected slate of officers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the awards front, we continued to make our annual service and
research awards. This year's ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Service Award
was presented to Kouichi Kishida, who has served the software
engineering community in many ways (including opening up many of the
relationships between Japan and the remainder of the software
engineering community). This year we awarded the Outstanding Research
Awards to Michael Jackson. The awards were announced at ICSE 2001 in
Toronto, with the presentation to Mr. Kishida taking place; Mr. Jackson
will receive his award at ESEC/FSE in September 2001 as part of his
keynote address. We also continued to award the Most Influential Paper
from ICSE N-10, which this year went to the ICSE-11 paper &amp;quot;Tolerating
Inconsistency&amp;quot;, authored by Bob Balzer. We made a number of awards to
students for travel support to SIGSOFT-sponsored conferences, under our
CAPS program; indeed, for ICSE 2001 in Toronto we increased our awards
to handle much more of the demand. As is common, several of the new ACM
Fellows are members of SIGSOFT.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2001-2002 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2002annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2002annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2001---june-2002">July 2001 - June 2002&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-alexander-wolf-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: Alexander Wolf, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has had a strong, but challenging year. A new set of officers
took their positions, with only the Chair (and, of course, the Past
Chair) having served previously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the awards front, we continued to make our annual service and
research awards. This year's ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Service Award
was presented to Prof. Lori Clarke of the University of Massachusetts.
We awarded the ACM SIGSOFT Outstanding Research Award to Dr. Gerard
Holzmann of Lucent Technologies. The awards were announced at ICSE 2002
in Orlando, with the presentation to Prof. Clarke taking place at the
conference. Dr. Holzmann will receive his award at SIGSOFT 2002 in
November 2002, and will give a keynote address. We also continued to
award the Most Influential Paper from ICSE N-10, which this year went to
the ICSE-12 (1992) paper &amp;quot;Towards a Method of Programming with
Assertions&amp;quot;, authored by David Rosenblum. We made a number of awards to
students for travel support to SIGSOFT-sponsored conferences, under our
CAPS (Conference Attendance Program for Students) program. Finally, our
initiative to have the program committees of SIGSOFT-sponsored
conferences name up to 10% of their papers as Distinguished Papers was
approved by the ACM awards committee.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2002-2003 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2003annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2003annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2002---june-2003">July 2002 - June 2003&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-alexander-wolf-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: Alexander Wolf, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has had a strong year, the second for the current
administration. The members of the executive committee have agreed to
avoid the time and expense of an election and will continue in their
roles for an additional two years. The bylaws are currently being
updated to, among other things, change the term of the elected committee
to three years with no option to continue. Past Chair David Notkin is
leading this effort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2003-2004 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2004annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2004annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2003---june-2004">July 2003 - June 2004&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-alexander-wolf-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: Alexander Wolf, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has had a strong year, the third for the current administration.
Conference attendance rates appear to be picking up a bit and we are
beginning to see the financial benefits of moving the bulk of our
newsletter, Software Engineering Notes, on line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the awards front, we continued to make our annual service and
research awards. This year's ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Service Award
was presented to Dr. Will Tracz of Lockheed Martin Corporation. We
awarded the ACM SIGSOFT Outstanding Research Award to Prof. Nancy
Leveson of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. The awards were
announced at ICSE 2004 in Edinburgh, with the presentation to Dr. Tracz
taking place at the conference. Prof. Leveson will receive her award at
SIGSOFT 2004 in November, and will give a keynote address. We also
continued to award the Most Influential Paper from ICSE N-10, which this
year went to the ICSE '94 paper &amp;quot;Formalizing Architectural
Connection&amp;quot;, authored by Robert Allen and David Garlan.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2004-2005 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2005annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2005annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2004---june-2005">July 2004 - June 2005&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-alexander-wolf-sigsoft-immediate-past-chair">Submitted by: Alexander Wolf, SIGSOFT Immediate Past Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has had a strong year, the last of the current administration.
Conference attendance rates appear to be continuing to pick up and we
are continuing to see the financial benefits of moving the bulk of our
newsletter, Software Engineering Notes (SEN), on line. We have begun to
move our sponsored conferences to CD-only proceedings. This has a
significant financial impact, as it means that our distribution of
proceedings to members (promised as two issues of SEN) can be done
through the Digital Library rather than the postal system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2006-2007 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2006annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2006annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2005---june-2006">July 2005 - June 2006&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-william-g-griswold-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: William G. Griswold, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has had an excellent year. A new set of officers took their
positions, with a large number of new faces coming on board. Due to the
growing number of elected positions being held by Europeans, our
European Liaison position was retired, and we instituted a South Asia
Liaison, reassigning our Asia Liaison to focus on North Asia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2006-2007 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2007annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2007annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2006---june-2007">July 2006 - June 2007&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-william-g-griswold-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: William G. Griswold, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT had an excellent year, maintaining the success of its
conferences while continuing to reach out to the community in many
dimensions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to the growing number of elected positions being held by Europeans,
our European Liaison position was retired, and we instituted a South
Asia Liaison, reassigning our Asia Liaison to focus on North Asia. Due
to the large growth in the number of conferences that we (co)sponsor and
cooperate with, we also reassigned responsibility for in-cooperation
conferences from our Vice Chair to the Secretary/Treasurer. We have also
more clearly delineated the roles of our at-large members, namely
awards, education, and digital library issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2007-2008 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2008annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2008annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2007---june-2008">July 2007 - June 2008&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-william-g-griswold-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: William G. Griswold, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT had an excellent year, maintaining the success of its
conferences while continuing to reach out to the community in many
dimensions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our major conferences continue to be strong - in attendance, sound
finances, and intellectual vibrancy. FSE 2007 was joint with the
European Software Engineering Conference (ESEC) in Dubrovnik, Croatia
last September, with Antonia Bertolino as the program chair and Ivica
Crnkovic as the general chair. ICSE 2008 was held in Leipzig, Germany,
with Wilhelm Schäfer as general chair, and Matthew Dwyer and Volker
Gruhn as program co-chairs. Both events featured SIGSOFT's successful
&amp;quot;Town Hall Meeting&amp;quot; format whereby we open the floor to an open
discussion on the issues of the day, while those present relax with
refreshments. At ICSE 2008, we experimented with a lunch format whereby
SIGSOFT reserved a separate room. This boosted attendance, but it seems
that many who attended were unaware of the special event.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2008-2009 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2009annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2009annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2008---june-2009">July 2008 - June 2009&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-alexander-wolf-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: Alexander Wolf, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT had an excellent year, maintaining the success of its
conferences during difficult economic times, while continuing to reach
out to the community in many dimensions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our major conferences continue to be strong - in attendance, sound
finances, and intellectual vibrancy. FSE 2008 was held in Atlanta,
Georgia, USA in November, with Gail Murphy serving as Program Chair and
Mary Jean Harrold serving as General Chair. ICSE 2009 was held in
Vancouver, Canada, with Stephen Fickas as General Chair, and Paola
Inverardi and Joanne Atlee as Program co-Chairs. Both events featured
SIGSOFT's successful &amp;quot;Town Hall Meeting&amp;quot; format whereby we open the
floor to an open discussion on the issues of the day, while those
present relax with refreshments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2009-2010 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2010annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2010annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2009---june-2010">July 2009 - June 2010&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-david-rosenblum-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: David Rosenblum, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT had another excellent year, maintaining the technical excellence
and financial health of its conferences despite increasingly difficult
economic times, while continuing to reach out to the community, with
increased attention given this year to the practitioner community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The numerous conferences and workshops we sponsor and co-sponsor
continue to be strong, both intellectually and financially. Our flagship
conference, ESEC/FSE 2009, was held in Amsterdam, The Netherlands, with
Hans van Vliet serving as General Chair and Valerie Issarny serving as
Program Chair. Our largest conference, ICSE 2010 (co-sponsored with the
IEEE Computer Society), was held in Cape Town, South Africa, with Judith
Bishop and Jeff Kramer as General Co-Chairs, and Prem Devanbu and
Sebastian Uchitel as Program Co-Chairs. The main social event at ICSE
was the Awards Banquet, where the SIGSOFT Chair presented several
important SIGSOFT awards and recognised the new ACM Distinguished
Members and Fellows from the software engineering community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2010-2011 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2011annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2011annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2010---june-2011">July 2010 - June 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-david-rosenblum-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: David Rosenblum, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT had another excellent year, both technically and financially in
2010-11. This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT activities over
the past year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWARDS THAT WERE GIVEN OUT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has a large awards program that recognises the many achievements
of the software engineering community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our prestigious service, research and education awards were presented
again this year at ICSE 2011 in Hawaii. The ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished
Service Award was presented to Jeff Kramer, in recognition of his many
years of service to ICSE (including General Co-Chair of ICSE 2010,
Program Co-Chair of ICSE 1999, and member and chair of the ICSE Steering
Committee), as well as his service to the leading archival journals in
software engineering (including Editor-in-Chief of IEEE Transactions on
Software Engineering and Associate Editor of ACM Transactions on
Software Engineering and Methodology). The ACM SIGSOFT Outstanding
Research Award was presented to Mary Shaw and David Garlan for their
work on the development and promotion of software architecture. As is
customary for this award, Mary and David will have the opportunity to
deliver a keynote address about their work at ESEC/FSE 2011 in Hungary.
Finally, the ACM SIGSOFT Influential Educator Award was presented to Ian
Sommerville, who is the author of probably the most widely used general
textbook in software engineering (currently in its 9th edition) as well
as co-author of two texts on requirements engineering and the Director
of the Graduate Academy of the Scottish Informatics and Computer Science
Alliance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2011-2012 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2012annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2012annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2011---june-2012">July 2011 - June 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-david-rosenblum-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: David Rosenblum, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT had another excellent year, both technically and financially in
2011 - 12. This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT activities over
the past year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWARDS THAT WERE GIVEN OUT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has a large awards program that recognizes the many achievements
of the software engineering community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our prestigious service, research and education awards were presented
again this year at ICSE 2012 in Zurich. The ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished
Service Award was presented to Alexander L. Wolf (Imperial College
London), in recognition of his extensive service to the software
engineering community through the many roles he has filled at ACM
(including SIGSOFT Vice Chair and Chair, SIG Governing Board Chair,
Software Systems Award Chair, ACM Secretary - Treasurer, and ACM Vice
President), as well as and his founding of the SEWORLD email list and
his service for the leading conferences and archival journals in
software engineering (including ICSE 2000 Program Co - Chair and
Associate Editor of ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and
Methodology and IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering). The ACM
SIGSOFT Outstanding Research Award was presented to Lori A. Clarke
(University of Massachusetts at Amherst) for her research on many key
techniques for software testing and analysis, including pioneering work
on symbolic execution for test generation, data flow test adequacy
criteria, and data flow analysis for software validation. As is
customary for this award, Lori will have the opportunity to deliver a
keynote address about her work at FSE 2012 in Cary, North Carolina, USA,
in November 2012. Finally, the ACM SIGSOFT Influential Educator Award
was presented to two recipients this year. The first recipient was Mehdi
Jazayeri (University of Lugano), who is the author of several
influential textbooks in software engineering in programming languages,
and who designed a highly innovative project - based undergraduate
curriculum as Founding Dean of the Faculty of Informatics at the
University of Lugano. The second recipient was David Notkin (University
of Washington), who has an outstanding record of producing top - quality
PhDs, many of whom have become leaders in the software engineering
community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2012-2013 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2013annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2013annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2012---june-2013">July 2012 - June 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-will-tracz-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: Will Tracz, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ACM's Special Interest Group on Software Engineering (SIGSOFT) had
another excellent year, both technically and financially in 2012-13.
This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT activities over the past
year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWARDS THAT WERE GIVEN OUT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has a large awards program that recognizes the many achievements
of the software engineering community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our prestigious service, research and education awards were presented
again this year at the International Conference on Software Engineering
(ICSE) 2013 in San Francisco, CA. The recipients are as follows:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2013-2014 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2014annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2014annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2013---june-2014">July 2013 - June 2014&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-will-tracz-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: Will Tracz, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ACM's Special Interest Group on Software Engineering (SIGSOFT) had
another excellent year, both technically and financially in 2013 - 14.
This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT activities over the past
year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWARDS THAT WERE GIVEN OUT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has a large awards program that recognizes the many achievements
of the software engineering community (see &lt;a href="http://www.sigsoft.org/)">http://www.sigsoft.org/)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our prestigious service, research and education awards were presented
again this year at the International Conference on Software Engineering
(ICSE) 2014 in Hyderabad, India. The recipients are as follows:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2013-2015 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2015annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2015annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="july-2014---june-2015">July 2014 - June 2015&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-will-tracz-past-chair">Submitted by: Will Tracz, Past Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ACM's Special Interest Group on Software Engineering (SIGSOFT) had
another excellent year, both technically and financially in 2014 - 15.
This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT activities over the past
year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWARDS THAT WERE GIVEN OUT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has a large awards program that recognizes the many achievements
of the software engineering community (see our home page for the most
recent awardees &lt;a href="http://www.sigsoft.org/)">http://www.sigsoft.org/)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fiscal Year 2016 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2016annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2016annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="fiscal-year-2016">Fiscal Year 2016&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-nenad-medvidovic-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by: Nenad Medvidovic, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>SIGSOFT seeks to improve our ability to engineer software by
stimulating interaction among practitioners, researchers, and educators;
by fostering the professional development of software engineers; and by
representing software engineers to professional, legal, and political
entities.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ACM's SIGSOFT had another excellent year, both technically and
financially in 2015-2016. This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT
activities over the past year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fiscal Year 2017 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2017annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2017annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="fiscal-year-2017">Fiscal Year 2017&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-nenad-medvidovic-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by Nenad Medvidovic, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>SIGSOFT seeks to improve our ability to engineer software by
stimulating interaction among practitioners, researchers, and educators;
by fostering the professional development of software engineers; and by
representing software engineers to professional, legal, and political
entities.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ACM's SIGSOFT had another excellent year, both technically and
financially in 2016-2017. This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT
activities over the past year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fiscal Year 2018 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2018annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2018annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="fiscal-year-2018">Fiscal Year 2018&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-nenad-medvidovic-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by Nenad Medvidovic, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>SIGSOFT seeks to improve our ability to engineer software by
stimulating interaction among practitioners, researchers, and educators;
by fostering the professional development of software engineers; and by
representing software engineers to professional, legal, and political
entities.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ACM's SIGSOFT had another excellent year, both technically and
financially in 2017-2018. This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT
activities over the past year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fiscal Year 2019 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2019annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2019annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="fiscal-year-2019-july-2018---june-2019">Fiscal Year 2019, July 2018 - June 2019&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-thomas-zimmermann-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by Thomas Zimmermann, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>SIGSOFT seeks to improve our ability to engineer software by
stimulating interaction among practitioners, researchers, and educators;
by fostering the professional development of software engineers; and by
representing software engineers to professional, legal, and political
entities.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ACM's SIGSOFT had another excellent year, both technically and
financially in 2018-2019. This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT
activities over the past year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fiscal Year 2020 Annual Report</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2020annualreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/annualrpt/2020annualreport/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-annual-report">SIGSOFT Annual Report&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="fiscal-year-2020-july-2019---june-2020">Fiscal Year 2020, July 2019 - June 2020&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submitted-by-thomas-zimmermann-sigsoft-chair">Submitted by Thomas Zimmermann, SIGSOFT Chair&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>SIGSOFT seeks to improve our ability to engineer software by
stimulating interaction among practitioners, researchers, and educators;
by fostering the professional development of software engineers; and by
representing software engineers to professional, legal, and political
entities.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This report provides a summary of key SIGSOFT activities over the past
year. The COVID-19 pandemic had a significant impact on the world and
also the SE community. Our hearts go out to all those affected by
COVID-19. Since the start of the pandemic, students and professors
switched to online teaching, software engineers now work from home, and
many conferences had to be cancelled or switched to virtual formats.
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to predict the long-term effects of the pandemic but
SIGSOFT remains committed to support its members during this difficult
time. On a positive note, despite the pandemic, the SIGSOFT community
had a strong technical year with many significant contributions and
SIGSOFT remains financially healthy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>