<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Impacts on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/impact/</link><description>Recent content in Impacts on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/impact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SIGSOFT Impact Project</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/impact/impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/impact/impact/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="impact-project">Impact Project&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Impact Project is an ongoing initiative whose goal is to determine the impact of software engineering research upon software engineering practice. The project organizes volunteers who are among the world&amp;rsquo;s most eminent software engineering researchers and practitioners to develop solidly researched documentation that will aid future research, education, and technology transition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Impact Project identifies and documents research contributions that have had substantial impact, determines the research modalities that have been successful, identifies technology transition approaches that have worked best, and anticipates directions that software engineering research might most effectively pursue, based on its history and positioning. Project results are useful to the software engineering research and practitioner communities, to other academic disciplines, to government funding agencies, and to the public by helping to objectively assess the software engineering community&amp;rsquo;s record of achievement. The project also provides a case study of how a scientific community works, and what approaches both hamper and improve its effectiveness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SIGSOFT Impact Project Whitepaper</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/impact/impactwhitepaper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/impact/impactwhitepaper/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-impact-project-determining-the-impact-of-software-engineering-research-upon-practice">The Impact Project: Determining the Impact of Software Engineering Research upon Practice&lt;/h3>
&lt;h5 id="leon-j-osterweil-carlo-ghezzi-jeff-kramer-and-alexander-l-wolf">Leon J. Osterweil, Carlo Ghezzi, Jeff Kramer, and Alexander L. Wolf&lt;/h5>
&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Has software engineering research had an impact on software engineering practice? If so, in which areas, and in what way? These are questions that are raised by practitioners in industry, members of funding organizations and researchers themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal of the Impact Project is to provide a scholarly study of the impact that software engineering research – both academic and industrial – has had upon practice. The reasons for doing this include: identifying the sorts of contributions that have had substantial impact, determining the research modalities that have been relatively more successful, and anticipating the directions that software engineering research might most effectively pursue, based upon its history and positioning.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>