<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Policies on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/</link><description>Recent content in Policies on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ACM SIGSOFT Policy on Program Committees</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/pcpolicy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/pcpolicy/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="acm-sigsoft-policy-on-program-committees">ACM SIGSOFT Policy on Program Committees&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="program-committee-members">Program Committee Members&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The program committee is responsible for objectively and thoroughly reviewing all submissions, for submitting timely, informative reviews that provide authors with feedback about their submissions, and for attending the program committee meetings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The program committee members should be recognized experts in the subject area of the event. For recurring events, at least one-third of the program committee membership should change. Most program committee members should not serve for more than three consecutive terms and in no instance should an individual serve more than four consecutive terms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guidelines for Running a SIGSOFT-Sponsored Meeting</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/meeting/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="guidelines-for-running-a-sigsoft-sponsored-meeting">Guidelines for Running a SIGSOFT-Sponsored Meeting&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The SIGSOFT &lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/execcontact">Executive Committee&lt;/a> is available to provide advice and counseling to event organizers. In general, we are happy to establish continuing relationships with organizers of regularly held events.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To help ensure that SIGSOFT events will be of high quality, the following guidelines have been adopted by the SIGSOFT &lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/execcontact">Executive Committee&lt;/a> and reflect what are considered to be best practices. The Executive Committee realizes that for certain events, alternative procedures may be warranted. In such cases the Meeting General Chair or Program Chair should contact the SIGSOFT &lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/contact">Vice Chair&lt;/a> and explain the desired change. Alternative procedures will be approved if the Executive Committee is reasonably assured that they will not adversely affect the quality of the event.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SIGSOFT Guidelines for Obtaining Cooperation Status</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/cooperation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/cooperation/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-guidelines-for-obtaining-cooperation-status">SIGSOFT Guidelines for Obtaining Cooperation Status&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT has two types of relationships with conferences and workshops:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/sponsorship">sponsorship&lt;/a> and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cooperation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The primary difference between the two is that sponsorship implies financial risk and responsibility on the part of SIGSOFT, while cooperation implies none. The following description of the in-cooperation relationship details SIGSOFT&amp;rsquo;s responsibilities, the meeting&amp;rsquo;s responsibilities and directions for applying for in-cooperation status.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="in-cooperation-status">In-cooperation Status&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The requirements for SIGSOFT in-cooperation status include the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SIGSOFT Guidelines for Obtaining Sponsorship Status</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/sponsorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/sponsorship/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sigsoft-guidelines-for-obtaining-sponsorship-status">SIGSOFT Guidelines for Obtaining Sponsorship Status&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT seeks relationships with events that complement SIGSOFT&amp;rsquo;s current sponsored events. Organizing your event with SIGSOFT brings numerous benefits to you and your event, the greatest of which is having the imprimatur of ACM and SIGSOFT, which sponsor the most prestigious conferences in all of software engineering. There are two types of affiliation for events that can be obtained from SIGSOFT:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>sponsorship; and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/cooperation">cooperation&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The primary difference between the two is that sponsorship implies financial risk and responsibility on the part of SIGSOFT, while cooperation implies none. Sponsorship may be joint with another organization, in which case the financial risk and responsibility are shared.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SIGSOFT-Sponsored Workshop Guidelines</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/workshop/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="guidelines-for-running-a-sigsoft-sponsored-workshop">Guidelines for Running a SIGSOFT-Sponsored Workshop&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT encourages and sponsors workshops in all areas related to software engineering. The general benefits of and requirements for SIGSOFT &lt;a href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/policies/sponsorship">sponsorship&lt;/a> are the same as for conferences. In comparison to a conference, however, a workshop is a technical meeting that:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>reports on work in progress,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>has a narrow focus,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>has sessions that enable interaction among workshop attendees, and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>is relatively low cost.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>SIGSOFT especially encourages workshops that collocate with SIGSOFT-sponsored conferences. One advantage of collocation is that the budgeting process is fairly simple, usually amounting to a one-page budget that can be handled using email.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>