<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cares on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/</link><description>Recent content in Cares on The ACM Special Interest Group on Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CARES Bylaws</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/bylaws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/bylaws/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>CARES mission statement&lt;/strong> The CARES committee was established to encourage a welcoming harassment-free research community at professional meetings sponsored by SIGSOFT. By its existence, it seeks to discourage bad behavior and offer a friendly ear for community members to discuss their experiences confidentially.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>CARES governance policies&lt;/strong> The remainder of this document outlines the policies for governance of the CARES committee, including chair rotation, membership, autonomy, and conflicts of interest on the CARES committee.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CARES Resources</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/resources/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>ACM Resources&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/special-interest-groups/volunteer-resources/officers-manual/policy-against-discrimination-and-harassment">Policy Against Harassment at ACM Activities&lt;/a>, by the ACM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/about-acm/reporting-unacceptable-behavior">ACM Harassment and Discrimination Reporting Procedures&lt;/a>, by the ACM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://services.acm.org/harass/harass.cfm">Form for reporting violations of ACM code of conduct&lt;/a>, by the ACM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/jKfAAU2-qs0">Addressing Harassment at ACM Events: Volunteer Training&lt;/a>, by the ACM&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Information on inclusion and diversity&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/www2.deloitte.com/us/en/insights/deloitte-review/issue-22/diversity-and-inclusion-at-work-eight-powerful-truths.html__;!!LIr3w8kk_Xxm!_b4N7uIztEGZI2NNVIfCL_fXdqGIoDproDX17-FkX9-josxIjI--5x1jDJJ_$">The diversity and inclusion revolution: Eight powerful truths&lt;/a>, by Juliet Bourke&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/www.sigarch.org/valuing-diversity-equity-and-inclusion-in-our-computing-community/__;!!LIr3w8kk_Xxm!_b4N7uIztEGZI2NNVIfCL_fXdqGIoDproDX17-FkX9-josxIjI--5wykFZfN$">Valuing Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion in Our Computing Community&lt;/a>, by Timothy Pinkston&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Information about implicit bias&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Current CARES Committee Members</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/committee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/committee/</guid><description>&lt;p>CARES is a subcommittee of ACM SIGSOFT. The role of the CARES committee is to serve as a resource comprising of well-known and respected people in the software engineering community who are approachable and willing to listen to and help people who experience or witness discrimination, harassment or other ethical policy violation, either at our events or related to ACM publications; the committee members can be a sounding board for these people and can provide advice on the steps necessary to have the matter further investigated by ACM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SIGSOFT CARES</title><link>https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/sigsoft_cares/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www2.sigsoft.org/cares/sigsoft_cares/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="purpose">Purpose&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>CARES is a subcommittee of ACM SIGSOFT. All ACM SIG events and communications abide by ACM’s &lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/special-interest-groups/volunteer-resources/officers-manual/policy-against-discrimination-and-harassment">policy against discrimination and harassment&lt;/a>. All ACM SIG publications abide by ACM’s policies on &lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/publications/policies/plagiarism-overview">plagiarism, misrepresentation, and falsification&lt;/a>; on &lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/publications/policies/coercion-and-abuse">coercion and abuse in the ACM publications process&lt;/a>; and on &lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/publications/policies/roles-and-responsibilities">roles and responsibilities in ACM publishing&lt;/a>. If a violation of any of these policies occur, ACM urges reporting the incident to the event chair or to ACM leadership, as indicated on those webpages. You may also report violations using the following forms:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>